Podcasting 2.0 for December 13th, 2024,
episode 204. Here comes the Universal app.
Hello, everybody, as we
get closer to Christmas.
I don't know, we all
just seem to be happier.
Don't you agree?
It is time for Podcasting 2.0.
This is where we talk
all things podcasting.
The past, the present, and the future.
We are, in fact, the only
boardroom that serves
Grandma's special eggnog
during the season.
I'm Adam Curry here in the heart of
the Texas Hill Country and in Alabama,
the man who eats Enterprise Software for
breakfast and spits it out at lunchtime.
Say hello to my friend on the
other hand, Mr. Dave Jones.
Hello, hello, hello, hello, hello,
hello, my friend Mr. Dave Jones, yes.
Hello.
Yes.
It was, you had a tough week, man.
The beginning was tough.
Yeah.
The ending is better.
The beginning was, you know, day jobs,
software meltdowns, but we survived.
The vendor is fixing things.
We're in better shape.
Whenever you take the time to
post on podcast, index.social,
that something's going on,
and I think you posted,
enterprise software is
the worst or something.
Let me see.
No.
It is.
And that's it.
You know, it's just like, just like
a random, you know, just like a,
like a Tourette's move.
You're like, just blast
something out onto, like,
I just need to share this with
people who will understand my pain.
Yeah, because just, just
having a bloop, bloop, bloop,
about four or five likes come
through, it makes you feel better.
It de-stresses.
Do you see those?
Because when you hit on, hit
the little, on the Mastodon,
you hit the little star button.
Do you follow those?
Do you watch those in your
notifications when that happens?
I just wonder if people do that.
Yeah, I've got, um, I use,
I don't know how other people use likes or
favorites or whatever you call it in the
Mastodon world, but,
or activity pub world,
but I use them when I don't really have
time or maybe the thing that I'm responding
to is not, maybe it doesn't need a
reply or I don't have time to reply.
And I just want to let the other
person know that I saw it.
Yes.
That's what I do as well.
I just wondered if people
actually view it that way.
So you do.
That's good.
I don't know.
Yeah, I, I, I tend to see that
that's what other people are doing,
but they may not be using
it in the same way.
I may be misinterpreting their results.
I like Bemrose in the, in the boardroom.
Nobody knows how to use
likes in the Mastodon world.
No, I think you're probably right.
No one, no one knows.
No one knows how that thing works.
Nobody knows what they're supposed to be.
Okay.
Hey, I had, like, I had a
brainwave before we started
the show and I just wanted to share it.
Okay.
I was listening to, uh,
to the, to the homework.
Hour.
I was listening to, uh,
Pod News Weekly Review,
hoping to hear something
about Dave Weiner,
but apparently they cut
all that out of the show.
Wait, they talked about
it and then cut it?
Yeah, pussies.
I wonder if it, I wonder
if it, I wonder if it,
I wonder if it's going to be in
the, wait, is it in the Pod News?
The Extended Edition?
Yeah, what is it?
Pod News Extra?
The Director's Cut.
Pod News.
I wonder if they left it
in the Pod News Extra.
Let me see.
Uh, no.
Okay.
All right.
Well, oh, wait, wait.
From the Cutter Noon Floor?
No.
Oh, anyway.
That's where they,
whatever podcast that's,
whatever feed that's in is the same one
where, um, the other six hours of Brian,
of Brian's, uh, Hive Talk is.
They're in the same place.
That's the one, yeah.
No, but it, it was about, uh, Apple's, uh,
podcast and that they have made it
progressive web app compatible.
Oh, I'm glad you brought this
up because I want to, um,
I've got thoughts on that too.
Okay.
Um.
No, no, you go, go ahead.
No, actually, because we've been dealing
with progressive web apps in our,
in our project.
Why don't you, I wouldn't mind
if you went first and then I,
then I can give you my brainwave
because it just might excite you.
I mean, I didn't have anything super,
uh, important other than just like,
I guess mine was more of a
political take on, on it.
It's, it's, it just makes me laugh that
that was their answer to getting something
onto the Android app store without paying
the, without, without paying the, the,
the Google play store tax.
Right.
It was by doing a PWA, which is exactly
what people have to do to get onto their,
to get around their tax.
It's just like this implicit
acknowledgement that it's a,
that the whole thing's just a, a rip off.
Um, but, but I wondered my, on
the technical side of things,
I didn't hear them say whether it was a, an
offline, whether it was offline capable.
No, it's not because, okay.
Because that's a big,
so there's a difference between
just being a PWA and being a PWA,
like a full function PWA, where
you have offline capability,
because that requires, that requires
what's called a service worker.
And that's a more complicated.
We used to have those in Amsterdam.
They had red lights in their windows.
Is that something different?
They take sats now.
Oh, nice.
Bolt 11.
Please.
What kind of wallet do you have?
Service worker.
Sorry.
Got to go to the next window.
Ellen URLP.
Well, so, you know, and I'm
thinking about this and yes,
I understand that what they're doing
and why they did it, but it just,
it hit me like a lightning bolt.
Because, you know, with the
project we're working on,
I've been showing people how to install
the Godcaster as a progressive web app.
And you can see that when
you say, oh, is it an app?
I say, yeah, let me install it for you.
And I do it.
And then they don't,
they're like, oh, great.
It's, I don't know how you did that.
I wasn't paying attention.
By the way, oh man, I've
learned just from time to time,
you should ask someone to do something and
watch how they do this on their phone.
So they're like, okay,
so how do I get to this?
And I'll give the boardroom the URL.
I say it's hellofred.fm.
And they'll open up DuckDuckGo.
And search for hellofred.fm.
And just type in hellofred.fm.
Actually, I'm going to do that.
Well, now, of course, right now
it's just a URL forwarding.
So it goes to mp3.nashownotes.com.
So that's completely useless because
it doesn't show up in search.
But people, it seems like people are
losing the understanding of a URL.
They're just going to, it's
either that or it's a Google app.
They're not even opening Safari.
They're not even typing
it into an address bar.
They're just, oh, well, I got
DuckDuckGo, which is also a browser.
And they just.
Can I, can I stop, stop the.
Stop the show?
Stop the flow?
Stop my important information?
Yes.
I want to.
Stop your important information.
Because I have more important information.
Your information always supersedes
my important information.
Why is, why does your Hello
Fred have two players in it?
Two players.
I don't understand this.
For me, it does.
Let me see.
This is totally inside
baseball at this point.
But I'm very, like, I have two.
No, I only, oh, that's interesting.
What is that?
I don't know.
What does your outline look like?
This, well, this is not an outline.
This is a static file.
Do you have, have you somehow
pasted the code twice or something?
That's very possible.
Hold on a second.
That's interesting.
It's like there's two players in here.
Yeah, I, that, I had
not even noticed that.
Hold on a second.
Yeah, Chad F. said he sees two also.
This is no good.
Hold on a second.
What's going on here?
Well, now we have to stop the show.
Yeah, stop the show.
What's the hellofred.html?
Hold on a second.
Where is this thing?
It's very possible that I did
something stupid like that.
Let me open it up.
Edit with Notepad+++.
Let's see.
How'd you get Notepad+++,
I only have Notepad+++.
That must be a later version.
So, Dave, do me a favor and just take a
look at that HTML file that it points to.
Okay.
Content with Page Source.
Player Assets.
This is old code.
Oh.
You need to paste, you need to cut,
you need to grab a fresh
copy of the player code.
Oh, well, that explains it.
Hold on a second.
Now, where do I put this?
This is actually really old, actually.
No wonder people are like,
how does this thing work?
I don't understand what this
thing is that you've built.
It makes sense.
This is pre-production.
So, I just do the dibs in the body?
That's where I do it?
If you just go to your widget,
I mean, not your widget,
but your player preview page
and do copy player code,
it'll give you what to paste in there.
Right, but I'm looking at
the, what do you mean?
I don't understand what you just said.
Like on your dashboard.
Yeah, but where do I put it in that page?
Do I put it in the body,
between the body tags?
Yeah, in the body.
That's what I meant.
Okay, hold on a second.
Hold on.
We're doing this on the fly.
We're doing it live.
Let's watch it update live in real time.
Hold on.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, he says.
I'm hitting refresh.
Okay, let's see.
Refresh.
I'm going to do a hard refresh.
Yeah, I'm doing a hard refresh.
Control-Shift-R for the uninitiated.
They're still doing the
same thing, I think.
You caching somewhere?
I might be.
I don't know.
You got old code.
Well, I just put the new code in.
Yeah, but it's still not that day.
Let me look at a local copy.
Yeah, the local copy works.
So it's probably caching.
Okay.
Yeah, local copy works.
Hard R.
Yeah, hard R.
Anyway, so thank you for
alerting me to that minor issue.
Let me see.
What does it do in the
progressive web app?
Yeah, no, it's good there, of course.
All right.
So I'm watching this nightmare unfold,
right, of how people, just in general,
a web browser doesn't even seem
to be in people's mind anymore.
Like, I'm not going to type
in, hello, Fred, period, FM.
No.
No, I'm just going to
search for everything.
But I'm safe because I got DuckDuckGo.
And so I'm just like, wow, the
web, the end of the web is near.
I don't know how to use a URL, but I know
I'm safe because I'm using DuckDuckGo.
So then I realized, and I
tried this out on Tina,
and we have been looking
at this all wrong.
We have been psyoped by Apple and
others into this progressive web app.
Because, of course, when I said to
Tina, you know, a progressive web app?
She said, I'm never going to use that.
That's a bunch of lefties, she said.
I'm not using a progressive web app.
That was her interpretation.
She'd never even heard of the term.
This has all been a political psyop.
Yes.
I'm like, well, this is no good.
And then all of a sudden it dawned on.
And I said, well, what do you think?
I don't want your left-wing app.
I don't want your lefty app.
I'm not interested in that.
She doesn't want a righty app either.
And I said, so what do you
think a universal app is?
She said, oh, that's an app that I
can install on any device anywhere.
No, that's the app where everybody
that uses it goes to heaven.
No, listen, you ruined my whole reveal.
Oh, sorry.
If you say to someone who has no
idea, we have a universal app.
Well, what is that?
Oh, this app works on any phone.
You don't have to worry about updates.
It synchronizes across your phones.
You can have it on an Android, on
an Apple, on a Windows, on a Mac,
on your tablet, on your iPad.
You don't have to worry
about, once you install it,
you don't have to worry about anything.
It synchronizes and it's
good to go forever.
You never have to log into your app store.
Well, how do I do it?
You install it like this.
And on every single browser, this
is the thing that they screwed up.
When you go to either save to
home screen or save to desktop,
it literally says install.
And thanks to that, people believe
that they just installed an app.
But it's not any app.
No, this is better than the app store.
It's a universal app.
Oh, oh, I want that.
Why do you want that?
It's a pain in the butt.
I've got to go download
an app for my iPad.
I have to download an app
for Windows and for Mac.
I can just do this once and
it synchronizes anywhere.
Yes, that's a universal app.
So I think we just get rid of this PWA
name and just call it a universal app.
The name Progressive Web App
is a horrible name, honestly.
Because what does it even mean?
Exactly.
Nobody even knows what it means.
What does it mean to PWA?
Like, it's like a progressive JPEG.
Do you remember those?
Progressive.
No, it was a progressive
GIF, I think it was.
Yeah, where it just like loads in a little
bit at a time so it starts out blurry.
It would take forever to see her boobs.
Everybody over 40 understands this joke.
For the first few seconds, it's
like watching Scrambled HBO.
Everybody over 40
understands that joke, too.
Scrambled HBO.
Who remembers that?
So, I mean, like, it's a terrible name
because nobody understands the progressive.
You know, the word
progressive means that it's
going to load parts at a time or whatever.
It's like, what is that even?
So here's my question.
Nobody understands this nomenclature.
Here's my question.
So when you hit a web page that you
can install as a universal app,
I believe there's a way to trigger
a pop-up that says install this.
I've seen it happen.
I don't, and maybe it's, I
don't know, maybe it's just,
I've seen it and people just doing it
and it's not an actual way to try.
I don't know what it is.
But you're saying that you don't
know how that install thing pops up?
How that triggers.
What I would love is if it
says, I mean, if you have a,
I'm just going to call it universal app.
I'm never calling it a PWA ever again.
If you have a universal app that
you want people to install,
which does require a small
tweak on the web page.
You want to have, now the thing that's a
little complicated is all the different
ways that browsers install this.
Some call it save to desktop.
Some call it, you know, iOS
calls it save to home screen.
Yet you get to it from a share menu.
Is there any way to bypass that first
step so that you just get that boom,
install screen?
Okay.
The install, let me.
So in iOS, you have to hit your share
button and you scroll down and it says,
add to home screen.
But then when you add to home screen,
I think it actually uses the
word install, doesn't it?
No.
Oh, Android does.
Android does.
Yeah.
iOS, you share sheet, add
to home screen, done.
That's all you get.
Android, add to, you know, Android,
you do the same thing you do.
I think it's, um, I forgot what
the, actually, I got my phone here.
Hold on a second.
I mean, the, the, I think that we
think we need to attack this nonsense,
these app stores head on by just saying,
and of course it doesn't work for
every single app because a lot of apps
need native features, but
for the stuff we're doing,
install this as a universal app and put
it right, right there.
One app works everywhere.
Never log into an app store again,
syncs across all of your devices.
Don't worry.
Updates are automatic.
Never have to do that.
Never.
I mean, the main thing, never
log into the app store.
I know on iOS, I see people
complaining all the time.
Oh, oh, I got, oh, I
got to get my password.
Oh, I got to use my, who
got to look at my face.
You know, it's like the app store is
always asking you to reauthenticate.
So I want to take the pain that they're,
that they're providing
and use the universal app
as something that's far superior.
And I can tell you, I'm on the
phone right now and I can,
I can immediately tell you why
nobody knows what a URL is anymore because
this is, I'm on the Android phone.
Uh, this is Android, uh, gosh,
14 or something like that.
And if I launch Chrome,
what I get is a start page and
there's a box, there's just a box.
I'm looking for the address bar.
There's no bar.
You just get a box that says, sir, in
the, in the box, in the input box,
it just says search or type URL.
Right.
So it's all, uh, what do they call it?
The universal, uh, universal
browser box or something like that.
That's what they've renamed the, what
we used to call the address bar.
Right.
Is now called something, something new.
It's they've called,
they've got a word for it.
It's like the universal box or something.
And it obscure, it, it, it munges
together search and Omnibar.
That's it.
Thank you.
Omnibar.
The Omnibar.
It munges search and, and addresses
together into one incomprehensible.
But not at the top.
It does it in the middle.
Yes.
It's not even at the top or the bottom.
It's just kind of like, you're like, what?
Right.
Well, on, on Chrome on windows, it has
a bar at the top and it, this is very,
very interesting what they've done here.
They have Chrome colon slash
slash what's dash new,
which I guess is their, their homepage.
Anyway, I, I just thought, and if
anyone can really experiment with this,
it's Sam Sethi with, uh, with true fans.
And I would say Ellen beats.
And there's a couple others.
I mean, just positioning it as
this, this is a universal app.
Here's how to install it.
No app store needed.
I think if you even say
that no app store needed,
people might see that as a benefit.
Oh, no app store needed.
Oh, okay.
I'll do that.
Cause in your head, you know,
uh, put one on my tablet.
I have to install it
again from the app store.
I have to get a different version,
all this different stuff.
It's just positioning.
And I think we've been
looking at it incorrectly.
Okay.
Your, uh, hello, Fred is,
uh, fixed proper now.
Yeah.
Good.
Looks right now.
So I'm going to the PWA.
So let me go.
Um, uh, yeah, it's add to home screen,
same terminology on, on Android.
Okay.
And what, yeah, then on
Android, after you hit that,
it pops up and it says
you get two options.
You get install or create shortcut.
So if you tap install, that's when you can
just put the, put the, drag it right on.
Yeah.
That works well.
And the button says install.
Install, which is beautiful.
Beautiful.
So anyway, I'm, I'm just
thinking it's language.
It's just language.
It's just a, a, a, a screen
or a page or something
and explains the benefits of why you
want to install a universal app
and then just put it in there.
I think just, so the same people who
don't know what an address bar is,
I think that we
can sigh up, sigh up them right back into
thinking, Oh, this is, I don't want it.
I want a universal app that
I can also install on my,
what I can install the same
app on my windows machine.
That's never been possible.
You can install it on your
iPhone and your windows machine.
People don't think about pretty good PWA.
Yes.
Experience.
And people, cause you know, people don't
think about these things the way do we do.
We're so deep into it, knowing what a PWA
is and, and all the, and you know, what
it can and can't do.
And we're just thinking about app stores
and, uh, you know, and to have, to be able
to, to have the same app
on most people in a,
at least in a business environment, we're
probably have a windows machine or,
you know, there's, there's a high,
high likelihood people have an
iPhone and a windows machine.
But even, even the
difference between not all
apps on your iPhone are
available on your Mac desktop.
That's an entirely
different app altogether.
So that is my, that is my word of the day.
Universal app.
The, um, that actually has, that's,
that's actually a pretty good,
that's actually a pretty
good lead into something
that I was thinking about.
I mean, you're talking about, uh, Dave,
Dave Weiner and, and the open source,
open source communities and,
and this kind of thing.
And, um, it was looking, as I saw, uh,
Russell from pod two posted
this morning about, you
know, he was upset about, um,
about things and that, you know,
he mentioned something
about splitting the community.
And I just, it just got me
thinking about this, you know,
about this whole topic because I
had a, I had a good call with,
and I want to talk about, uh,
what me and Oscar talked
about yesterday as well.
Um, I had a good call with Oscar
yesterday cause we were trying to, um,
you know, come
to the, come to some conclusion or trying
to figure out what to do about, uh,
about what,
uh, Bumi from Albie was talking about with
the, uh, LN address options file spec.
Um, but sort of related to that, I
started, when I saw Russell's thing,
it reminds, I guess
my first thought that I guess the first
thought that I had was, you know,
splitting communities
doesn't really happen unless you have a
sort of a self-proclaimed leader of, of,
of, yeah, self-proclaimed leaders
in those communities that,
that kind of lean into
their egos and then,
um, do something negative.
And I don't, I'm not concerned about
any, about things being, you know,
splitting the podcasting 2.0 community
because, uh, we don't have any leaders,
but nobody's in charge.
Um, and when you don't have any leaders,
even self-proclaimed ones, uh, there's,
I mean, there's just, there's no,
there's the splitting doesn't happen.
So, um, it's just like, it's
just this sort of like, uh,
libertarian hydra thing that we
have going on, you know, here where
there's not, nobody's really,
nobody's really in charge.
We just kind of duke it
out and then figure out,
and then something emerges and when, and
sort of quote unquote wins.
And it's not all in a lot, it's not
always what makes every, you know,
everybody happy, but it's
just the way that it goes.
And it, you know, that's
just true with open source.
I mean, open source is a, uh, I heard, um,
like I heard a talk by
Thomas DiLorenzo one
time where he was talking about.
Who is Thomas DiLorenzo?
Uh, he's an Austrian economist.
Um, I think he's at,
I think he was at George Mason
university and I'm not sure where he is.
Must be a Bitcoiner.
I don't think so.
No, I think he's a gold standard guy,
but he was talking about the, uh,
the nature of
the, of the firm, you know, just, just
the, you know, companies in general and,
and, and monopoly and antitrust.
That's his big sort of topic
is monopoly and antitrust.
And he describes, uh, he describes,
um, competition within a firm, uh,
as because, you know, he's
setting up this nature, like you have
competition between firms in a market.
Then you also have this competition that
takes place inside of a firm where,
and he calls it like this
dynamic rival risk process.
And I always, that, that, that
phrase always stuck with me,
a dynamic rival risk process.
That's what open source communities are.
They're a dynamic rival risk process,
uh, in search of a single standard,
you know, getting from,
getting from two, three, 10,
27 ideas to eventually get
to a protocol reference or
standard is unbelievably messy
and sometimes frankly impossible.
Uh, I mean, sometimes you
try to go through this
dynamic rival risk
process of people having
differences of opinions and, uh,
and proposing different protocols
and that kind of thing.
And you really never can
come to a, come to a, uh,
conclusion where everybody's on board.
That's also a thing that happens.
Um, and, but that's, but you
know, that's why we do it.
Honestly, we do it.
People who love open source, we don't
just do it because we like, um,
software or coding or,
uh, standards or anything like that.
I mean, like we know that's,
that's not, there's,
if there was not a rivalry
sort of competitive
process to it, it would not be
as enticing and as fun as it is.
You know, people who love open
source are like hot rotters,
hot rotting versus like
just modding or restoring.
So like, if you're like, if you're a
person who likes tinkering with cars,
you might, um, you might
like, and you want to put some more, you
know, a hundred more horsepower in your,
in your Mitsubishi Mirage
or something like that.
You know, you may go to,
you may like go to a bunch of
websites and find some parts that
somebody told you to get
on a forum and you buy
them and you install them on the weekend.
Okay.
That's, that's fine.
You're kind of a car guy.
That's not a hot, that's
not what hot rotters do.
You know, hot rotters
don't have the luxury of
buying off the shelf
parts most of the time.
So we like the truck I drove to work this
morning was my wife's a 67 F two 50.
This thing is a, it's a 67.
It's got a blower.
It's got a blower on the hood, doesn't it?
It's got, she's got a blower.
Tell me she's got a blower.
Um, almost it is a force.
There's a four 60 in it.
Yeah.
With a, with a cam, uh, with an
aftermarket cam and this thing will,
it will do easily 150 miles an hour.
It is terrifying.
It rips the bricks right
out of the pavement.
I bet when you take off of
that thing, it is so scary.
25% throttle on the highway
and you're doing 70.
Wow.
It is unreal.
And the thing is, it's got a, it's
got a four 60 out of a 1974 in it.
So it's a 67 truck with a 74 engine.
We're already getting off
the reservation here.
Kind of.
You know, you go into the part shop and
you're like, uh, you know, I need a, uh,
you know,
I need this, uh, I need this flex
plate, uh, for the, and they're like,
okay, what year?
I'm like, uh, well, which one do you want?
The one for the truck or the one for
the, so, you know, like, so if you're,
if you're
doing that, you know, if you're a hot
rodder and you're mixing, matching, uh,
let's say
you want to put a, a, a four R 70 W out of
a 95 onto a four 60 from a 74, well, you
better be ready to go to the machine
shop and break out the micrometer.
Yeah.
You're going to have to do some stuff.
There's, there's not going
to be a flex plate that
exists that will interface that crankshaft
to that torque converter.
So you are literally going to
have to build it from scratch.
That's what open source is.
I wanted to say something
about Dave Weiner.
It applies to Russell
because I've identified for
over 20 years of identified
Dave Weiner has a bug.
He has a software bug.
It's in his processing and
I've tried to understand it.
I've tried to route around it.
Um, I, I think I get, in fact, I'm,
I'm very happy he has this
bug because that's how you
and I met 15 years ago.
Yep.
Amen.
And amen, indeed.
And it's a conspiracy loop.
He believes the world is against
him at all times, forever.
Big companies are out to steal his ideas.
You know, people are running away.
It's a, it's a loop.
It's a, I've seen, I've
seen him go through it.
Luckily he, he, he writes a lot.
So you can see the loop happening
over and over and over again.
So when he complains about the name,
that's just an excuse for him
to not engage in a project
that in fact, he's not in charge of.
That is exactly what you just said.
Yeah.
Um, when he's not in charge
or someone says something
that makes them look like they want
to be a leader where they're just
contributing or throwing out an idea.
He got, he, the loop kicks in and I've
seen this over and over and over again.
And so when he said, well, podcasting
too, it's insult, whatever he said,
that's the name of this podcast.
Nowhere, I mean, people have picked
it up and colloquially, collo, collo,
collo, what's the term?
Colloquially.
Colloquially use the term for what
we're doing, but it's podcastindex.org.
It's podcastindex.social.
The namespace is at
podcastindex-org at GitHub.
There's nowhere does it say that
this is a podcasting 2.0 community.
It's just a crutch.
It's just an excuse for him not to
participate because he's not given what he,
he, he says he wants a leadership role.
My software, I want to do it.
I run it.
That's what he does.
And it's not malicious.
It's just a bug.
And so when he says, uh, OPML
predates all this stuff, well, yeah.
Okay.
So does cassette tapes, you know?
Um, it's like, by the way, OPML,
that's where you and I met.
We love the format.
We even built a namespace
for it called SOPML.
People might want to look that up.
It's a phenomenal, the
first index at ipotter.org,
the first podcast index
was a hyperlinked outline
processor markup file, an OPML file,
which was just spectacular to use.
I mean, you literally could paste in nodes
of stuff that other people maintained.
And, and I, I love that.
And it was so exciting because
things would update down the line.
It was basically one big directory
outline that multiple people could,
could work on.
And as we were, you and I were
in, I forget what the group was.
Yeah.
And we had instant outlining where
all of a sudden the node would,
you'd hear a bleep and a node would glow.
And that would be an outline where you
could write stuff and it would have
automatically updated.
And I could see what you had
just written in an outline form.
I think in outlines, I think
a lot of real time chat.
Yeah.
I think a lot of developers think in
outlines because that's, you know,
code is kind of outline in a way.
And a folder hierarchies are outlined.
So I, and I, and we built software.
Well, anyway, so we were using that
and I don't remember what it was,
probably something I said.
And then he just pulled the
plug on the whole thing.
Like, Oh, I'm done.
People try to take it away from me.
This bug is unstop, unstoppable.
Only he can, can troubleshoot
and fix that bug.
So it's, it is exactly what you're saying.
When there's no leader,
people, some people get,
have this bug and they don't get it.
And they're frustrated
and think that, you know,
the leaders are working behind the scenes.
It's conspiratorial loop.
I'm telling you, I've
seen it over and over.
And over again, and it's
incompatible with what we're doing.
Again, I'm very pleased that, um,
that because of that, you and I met.
And so we built the, built the freedom
controller completely based on OPML.
Not once.
I mean, he knows, he knows is there.
He never looked at it.
He doesn't care.
He's never looked at
the stuff we're doing.
He's never looked at podcast index.org,
which is some of the stuff
he's advocated for over
and over and over again, but he's
not in the leadership council,
whatever that is, the Starfleet command.
So it's not easy.
And we're not either.
That's the point.
No, that's the point.
So it's, it's not easy for everybody to
comprehend that, but, uh, I've given up.
I'm trying to fix people like that.
And in a way this, so now this,
cause James, then I could have,
I should have warned James.
I didn't know he was going to do it.
I said, don't, don't,
you're wasting your breath to go
and tell Dave Weiner to look at
a GitHub about something
that he invented a whole
long time ago and try
to tell him it's good.
Cause it has the same outcome.
Cause he, he's like, I wasn't consulted.
That's basically what he said.
And by the way, you're insulting me
and you're trying to hijack stuff.
I've heard this for 20 years
from him and I still love him.
He's, he, he is, he is a child of God.
So I can't see him any
other way than that.
And I love him, but we may just
not be able to work with him.
But OPML versus pod roll, the
way we have it implemented.
Yeah.
It's like Betamax versus VHS.
Guess what?
Betamax definitely was superior.
What?
V 2000, the P 2000, the
Phillips system was superior.
VHS one, give it up.
You know, that's where all the porn
guys started to release on VHS.
And so it was the content
as usual that drives it.
So if people are publishing and that's
even in, we adhere to Dave Weiner's,
Dave Weiner's, um, rules
for standards makers.
The name doesn't matter.
It's like right at the top.
Yeah.
It's one of the first ones.
So, and if something's
working, then it's working.
The, the, the other one is
interop is all that matters.
Yes.
Interop, interop is the thing that you,
that is the crux that you can't control.
And this is, this is always where open
source hits the rocks is, is, is where,
so like right now we have, um, and
this is, this is apropos to what, um,
Russell is, is talking
about and doing as well.
Cause he's, he's building
software for, uh, boost, uh,
boost gram metadata and
that kind of thing.
And I think, and that's where a
lot of where he got, you know,
I got frustrated with is in, but, but
you can't, you, you can build stuff,
but you can't control the outcome.
That's see, that's, that's the issue.
And that's really the heart of it when,
so you've got, you know, found, uh,
fountain and wave lake who are big
players and in the value for value,
um, bitcoins ecosystem.
And they're pushing forward with Noster
because that's the thing that fits the
system that they've built.
And they believe in that protocol and they
believe in that system and then they're
going, they're going to
push through with that.
And then you have, uh, other,
you know, other people, uh,
Alex has proposed to spec for the boost
metadata tag in the feed and then, um,
uh, protocol to go, um,
to go along with that.
And you have Russell, who's
building his software.
Uh, I forgot the name of it.
It's like a pod two.
Yeah.
That's the company, but I mean, it's like,
it's like LBG or something like that.
I can't, I can't remember BGL BGL.
Okay.
So you got these, you got people building
different things that are trying to do the
same thing or similar things.
And you can't, and various people within
a community are going to align themselves
with the thing that they think is makes
the most sense or the thing that fits the
thing they already did.
And you can't control the outcome.
So there's this sense that you build it
and you advocate for it, but then you,
you, you always end up having to sit
back and just hope that it takes root.
Yes.
And sometimes it does.
And sometimes it doesn't.
Well, I'll tell you how it does.
I'll tell you how it does.
And I've said this time and time again,
it's always comes down to the content.
So I guarantee you whatever Stephen Bell
builds and puts into sovereign feeds,
I'm going to use because I
can't hack something together.
So when I have content and I'm publishing
content and by publishing content,
that's just not my MP3 files.
That's my entire RSS feed.
That's my content.
And how I want it, what I
want it to do is my content.
Now, if enough people are
interested in my content,
they will want to read
and parse my content.
It always comes down to that, no matter
how many spiffy demos we have that.
And I'll say that is what has
driven this community from day one.
If you recall, we started this and it was
a lot of frustration, mainly from my side.
And Martin came in, Martin from Denmark,
and he tried to build basically
what Stephen Bell did.
He tried to build a publishing system that
sucked in your existing feed and then
allowed you to add the new
namespace tags and pump it out.
And it was very difficult.
It was a very complicated thing.
And Stephen Bell came in and whatever
special processing he has in his brain,
he was able to put it together.
And so as far as I can tell, we have
driven whatever Stephen Bell put in there.
Not always his ideas, by the way.
I mean, he has stuff in there from other
people that hasn't taken root yet,
but it's in there.
And it's not all his stuff,
but publishing matters.
Well, so, you know, I mean, with with
Steve, like Stephen's a good example.
And I talked about, you know,
we me and Oscar talked about this yesterday
is Stephen put in the chat attribute.
Yes.
Into the into the live item
tag, which was not in the spec.
No, but but because so there's
two things with Stephen.
He put that in when it was not in the spec
and that that guy that really solved a
problem and people picked it up.
It was a quick solution to a
to a to a to a real problem.
Picked it up.
Got it.
Got the job done.
We have a real spec for it now.
But that but that got the job done.
Yeah.
The other thing he did was with the real
time with live streams with socket.io.
We still don't have a real spec.
We don't have a spec for that.
We don't have a spec.
There is no spec for now.
There's a spec for the format
of the messages you receive,
but there's no spec for how for
how you construct the socket.
The the delivery, the transmission
protocol is not defined.
So he's still using socket.io and
people are tapping into that.
And, you know, I hope we
can standardize something.
But it's gotten on the back
burner for a long time.
But that's that's just a couple of examples
of how when things things just naturally
get a momentum and they just
go and you can't stop them.
We we had so we when I was talking to
Oscar yesterday, we talked about, OK,
what are we going to do?
Because I was confused by Boomi's
email when he said that he wasn't.
I don't know.
I don't even want to quote him because
I was just confused, evidently,
because he said that that's
not what he was saying.
I thought he was saying that Albie would
not support an address options lookup file,
but that's evidently not what he meant.
So that's fine. But so originally, let me
let me let me give the conclusion first.
Conclusion is I think what we're going to
do is just scrap the LN address options
options dot well-known file.
Instead, we're just going
to have to the original
proposal for lightning address was this.
It was just add another value recipient
type with with the LN address option.
And that will refer to a lightning address,
which is a bolt 11 LN URLP lookup,
which is interestingly what I
already have in my sovereign feeds,
which is already working.
OK, so that the what we tried to do was
we the the original idea was lightning
address was going to be that just a way
to interface with bolt with LN URLP.
We transitioned to this LN address options
lookup file because Roy came in and said,
hey, why don't we take this opportunity to
future proof all this all this stuff and
create a sort of abstraction layer where
we can have an options file that you can
look up and see how to pay somebody.
And it can have decent or bolt 11 or bolt
12 or whatever comes in the future that
seemed that seemed like a lot
of people liked that idea.
I liked that idea.
And he seemed to think that we
could get it into the LN URL spec.
But then, you know, the reality, though,
and I agree with Boomi on this and is there's
probably not going to have any there's
probably not going to be any support
for it on the broader wallet front.
So I understand the I understand the
hesitancy on on Albie's part because they're
like, well, you know, I mean, I
think what Boomi was saying is, yes,
we will begrudgingly support this.
But I don't like it because I don't think
anybody else is going to any book is going
to because this this stuff is already built
and we know what sort of entrenchment
looks like in a in a in
a spec or a standard.
And that's in, you know, and he's right.
So basically, if you're so the saving grace
here is if you were building to the LN
address options file already, then
if you were building to that spec,
you are already having to do sort
of a check and say, all right,
does this back end support
the options look up?
Yes or no.
If not, fall back to LN URLP.
If so, look up the options file.
Right.
Well, now you can just
get rid of that check.
Right.
You just can just just look at type.
Yeah.
So now, yeah, now you don't
have to look have a list
of supporting hosts and
this kind of thing.
It's just a straight LN URLP all the time.
And then we'll just we'll
just go forward with that.
And, you know, hope that in the future is
something is some sort of bolt 12 thing
happens that the LN URLP spec will
itself update to handle that.
And we will just write that for free.
OK, well, I think that's what created the
most confusion was the LN address part in
the we don't have to go into history.
But it's interesting where
it came from initially as
to the people who don't
really want it right now.
But I'm all for this.
That seems like a like a
simple, elegant solution.
And Stephen B is asking, is
the type LN URLP or node?
No, the type is still going to
be LN address because it's just.
Oh, OK.
It's still a lightning address.
Oh, so we deal with.
OK, so no changes.
You still call it LN address
when when LN address.
OK, all right.
Got it.
Yeah.
The LN address is that terminology
is not going to change for the type.
You're just going to be doing it.
You're just going to know
ahead of time when you see
that it's going to be a
bolt 11 LN URLP lookup.
Got it.
So I say disregard my dumb comment.
Stephen B.
OK, there we go.
Well, that's good.
That I feel like, you know,
something is moving now.
It feels like we're moving ahead.
And I see a lot of a lot
of positive wordage around
the I think the Alex
Gates metadata solution.
Am I saying that correctly?
Yeah.
The meta boost or boost
metadata, whatever it is.
Yeah.
So, I mean, briefly, how does that work?
What exactly?
So, you know, we talked about this
Oscar Oscar a little bit, too.
And, you know, they really want
to do the Noster Nip thing.
And, you know, I was like,
hey, you have a product.
Build what you need for your product.
And then we as a community can figure
out how to interface with that.
You know, the thing is,
I mean, specs are great.
But I think they also like there's an interop
thing that has to happen here where we
can build a thing to interface with
each other rather than, you know,
everybody has to, you know.
Because like this, like with
Russell's, you know, BLG thing,
I think we could use something
like the meta boost API,
API spec to interface with
a lot of these things.
Like, I think, I think that's the
interface layer that we can have.
We just got to figure out how to do it.
Okay.
And so, yeah, I don't think,
I just don't, I don't,
I guess I just don't see them really,
I don't see that as competitor specs.
Well, I mean, we have bridges already
between ActivityPub and Noster,
which seems to work reasonably well.
Well, the one thing I, the one thing I
expressed to, to Oscar is I'm like, well,
I think, you know, I think developers are,
are going to hit a wall of
complexity with WebSockets.
Because WebSockets are just not as
easy as just doing an HTTP look.
I've rid my entire house of WebSockets.
When we moved in here, I said,
get rid of all those WebSockets.
I don't want a single one.
Clean as a whistle.
Clean.
Yes.
And so, you know, I was
like, well, you know,
most socket programming is harder than
just doing a get request and, or a post.
And most people know how to, most
developers already know how to do those.
And so what he said was, well, why
don't we, he said, why don't I do this?
He said, why don't, why don't I go ahead
with, with what we're doing with Noster?
And then I'll put in HTTP support
where you can do lookups, uh,
with just HTTP requests.
Perfect.
And so I'm like, you know, if, if
you can do that, it'd be great.
You know, and so then, you
know, we can figure out.
So that's, that's one way we can figure
out how to, yeah, just like, uh,
like Alex is saying, you don't, then
you don't have to hook into the stream.
Then you can just, then
you can deal with HTTP.
Right.
And we can put something in
front of that, that looks, uh,
like a more generalized, um, interface
layer or something like that.
I don't know.
Well, I think this is all, I mean,
I've been so focused on trying to just
get this, just get the payment part.
Like, you know, that,
that Ellen address options thing resolved
that I think the, the, the boost date,
uh, metadata, that'll be sort
of like next or whatever.
But I'm not too worried about it.
I think people can build
what they want to build.
And I think, uh, a generalized accepted
standard will come out of it that we can
all, that we can all use.
And it, you know, we'll, we'll
figure out how to make it work.
Well, I, I must say that, you know,
so I'm already publishing with a, uh,
a mini split to my strike wallet.
And, uh, believe me, I will be jumping up
and down when I see payments come through.
And then if I, and then if I know
where to get the information,
I'll be even happier.
Yeah, that's, um, yeah, I think, I just
think we'll, I think we'll get there.
I think so too, Dave.
I do.
You know, I, I just had like this,
I've seen this happen so much before
where we've gone through this process of,
of, of, of this, how many times?
A lot.
And we, we always get something
at the end of it that works.
Um, so I'm, I'm not worried about it.
We'll, we'll figure something out.
Uh, well, we do have an answer
to this one pressing question,
which is Ellen address.
And that is thankfully a solved.
Good.
Um, I am not changing my mind on this.
I'm done.
I personally am done with this discussion.
Everybody else can duke it out
if they want, but I'm out of it.
Can we celebrate with a song?
Yeah, I think that's a good idea
because Monday, December 16th,
live from Antones in Austin, Texas,
Adam Curry's Booster Graham Ball Live.
It will be streaming on all
of the modern podcast apps.
I'm very excited.
We have a lot of really cool bands who
are going to be performing and a lot of,
uh, developers actually who will be
showing up, uh, in the audience.
I got a guest list that's longer
than, uh, the Queens, I tell you.
This guy will be performing Abel James,
live while I'm alive on podcasting 2.0.
Well, I'm alive.
I like that guy.
I like him a lot.
I'm glad it was five minutes because,
uh, I had to run to the, uh,
fridge and grab a drink.
Oh, good.
He, uh, he's also, he does podcasts
and he's, he's, uh, he's on fire, man.
He's excited to be, uh, be
at, uh, Antones Monday.
Tickets still available.
Get them while they last.
That's right.
It's a hot, it's a hot ticket.
It'd be great.
Thank you for boosting Chad
F and, uh, Silas on Linux.
Appreciate that.
I wanted to just say one other quick
thing about, uh, you know, the, uh, ever,
ever ongoing video, video, video.
I just have two things to say about it.
I need video, I need video.
If video, what is the most
successful podcast category, Dave?
I think you know the answer to this.
True crime.
If it's so important to have
video to be successful,
why don't all true crime
podcasts have video?
Because it's not true.
Thank you.
Second.
So that's one.
Do you know what the, uh, CPM,
the advertising rate is cost per
thousand of a audio podcast?
You can give me an average.
Um, isn't it usually somewhere
around like 22, $23?
Yeah, let's just say 20.
We'll just take it.
We'll low ball it.
20 bucks.
What is the CPM you get on YouTube?
Oh, I reckon it's like maybe five bucks.
Three.
That was high.
So what are y'all talking about?
Enough said.
Backslash.
End rant.
Period.
Yes.
Done.
Uh, I would like to, if we
have, uh, do we have time?
We have time.
Okay.
I want, I just want to
throw this on the radar.
I think it's time to
start thinking about, uh,
super chat transcripts for live items.
That's funny because I put
in my notes for next week.
That'll be today.
Chat transcripts for live
items dash pod ping D.
I don't know why that's, that was,
that's the line I wrote down on
the last show, last board meeting.
Okay.
Um, man, I got two of those things to
talk about and I don't know which, uh,
let's do, uh, chat
transcripts for live items.
Tell me what you're thinking.
Okay.
That's good.
Cause that'll let me get, I've still,
I've been too busy to get
pod ping D up and run.
That'll give me another week to get that.
Okay.
I'll leave it on the list though.
I'll leave it on the list.
Okay.
All right.
Uh, so, you know, I think we, I
think it's something we all want.
Clearly we want a, a transcript
for, uh, you know, for like for in,
in this instance, we're doing a
live, we're doing a live item.
We're doing a live show and then,
uh, so we need, uh, we would want,
we would want some way for when this
live show becomes a normal podcast.
So when it goes, when it
gets transferred from
a live item to a regular item in the feed,
we need some way to preserve the chat if
the podcast, if the podcaster so desires.
Right.
A replay.
You're talking about a chat replay.
Chat playback.
Yes.
Playback.
So not transcripts is the wrong term, but
it can't, but, but see, it could be a VTS.
I mean, it could be a VTT.
I mean, like, oh, that's just the format.
I'm just saying it's not, it's not
really, it's, but when you say, when I,
when I heard this, I was like, I didn't,
the word chat fell away from me.
I just like transcripts.
So we have to do live transcripts.
I was thinking completely incorrectly
about what, what the topic was.
So when you say chat replay, I get it.
Yeah.
Chat.
I called it a chat transcript,
but it could be a chat playback,
whatever you want to call it.
And that's cool.
Yeah.
We, so, you know, we need some way.
So there's two, there's two issues.
Um, there's two issues.
There's one's going to be time sync.
So where do you know, there
has to be some way to sync up.
And Alex is saying that there's,
uh, in the chase, he's, he's,
he's saying in the boardroom that
there's some solutions for that.
So we need some way to sync up the,
uh, so, so, you know, okay, here's,
here's where the episode starts, but, but
in, in, in the, in the ether of, of time,
where did the chat
start and we need to make sure those
things are, are, are, uh, simultaneous.
And then, uh, the other
thing is how to preserve a,
a reference to the live items such that,
you know, such, such that, you know,
that this transcript of the
chat belongs to this item.
So if that trans, you know, if
that, if you're recording it as a,
so let's say IRC, okay.
This, so we're the boardroom that is IRC.
So something would be recording
this IRC or, you know,
interfacing with the IRC server to
get the transcript of the IRC
chat for this, this show.
Um, the, so then you would need some
way to say, okay, this thing goes now,
this light, that live item that had,
let's say, and I'm just spitballing here,
this light item, a live
item that had this GUID
is now this item that
has this other GUID and
we need to reference
this chat transcript file.
Well, isn't, isn't, isn't that exactly
what we already do with, um, uh,
for with a value
time split because I'm, I am setting
a queue for each value time split.
And now I have a tool for
that called the split kit,
but that seems like something that,
you know, from a publishing
side, you just have to do.
The boardroom's going nuts because
they're like, well, Hey, this is,
I don't want this, the
boardroom published.
I'm not saying that we're going
to do that for this show.
I'm just saying for people that want
it, you know, for shows that want it.
So like, if somebody's doing
a show that wants to do this,
I feel like we need a spec for it.
Um, it reminds me of the old days
of video where you, you know,
I'd be interviewing Paul
McCartney and there'd be
a guy there with a huge,
big reel to reel video tape machine
and a guy next to him with a Nagra.
And then I'd have to look in the camera
and go three, two, one, and make a clap.
Everybody claps.
Make one clap so they can sync it
up, sync it up with the video.
Yeah.
No, I mean, maybe, I don't know.
You know, we'll have to, we'll have to see
what we can, you know, what's out there.
What, what Alex is talking about.
Um, so, you know, there's,
I don't want this.
I want the board, like for this show, the
boardroom is that's, you got to show up.
This is secret.
Yeah.
This is, this is, no cone of silence here.
No, no worries.
Yeah.
If you want to know,
if you want to know what's going on
in the boardroom, you got to show up.
But I can see a show like no
agenda with the troll room.
Oh, so many people would
love to see their trolls.
They would love, I know they would,
they would, ah, this is great.
Look, I trolled Adam and he
responded, you know, but also, um,
there's a lot of stuff that
they, they give me that I then
use immediately in the show.
I mean, I can see a lot of
podcasts that would like that.
Not this one, but I can
see a lot that would.
Well, it's a very popular thing on, uh,
on YouTube and Twitch and
all these other places.
There's, there's just clearly,
there's clearly use cases for this.
So, um, you know, I, I just
want, I think those are the,
those are the hurdles is getting,
getting time sync correct.
And then, uh, in figuring
out the references.
Right.
Uh, and so I just wanted
to put that on the radar
so there's something we can think about.
Um, I'm probably going to, I'll post
a discussion item about it, uh,
just to get the ball rolling.
Yeah.
And then, yeah, yeah.
Cause I, I, it's a, it, we're
almost there with super chat.
That's like the last thing that,
what reminded me of it is I watch
the local weather or weather
guy, uh, James Spann does a,
does a morning weather, uh,
briefing every morning at like 5 a.m.
And I just, I watch it pretty
religiously and he's always got a chat.
I watched the replay at like six
or six 30 and he's always got, uh,
does the chat from earlier?
He's the live chat comes through and it's
being replayed while I'm watching it.
I'm like, you know, this,
this, we need this.
This is a missing hole.
There's a hole.
I like it when, uh, if I, I don't watch
him a lot anymore, but Scott Adams,
if I watch him, I'll watch
him with the chat replay.
I enjoy that.
Yeah.
I can see it.
Sometimes I like it.
Sometimes I don't.
It, I just, I selectively
turn it on or off.
Yeah.
Cotton gin has been asking
for this for years.
Well, how come you haven't built it yet?
Cotton gin.
You're the IRC guru.
You are the IRC guru.
Come on, man.
Come on.
Let's get it going for no agenda.
It'd be hilarious.
Yeah.
He's a, he already has the, the listen
calculator for me and all that stuff.
He's got all kinds of cool
IRC things he's doing.
He says, I'm dumb.
Okay.
Boy, that'll be fun to
watch on the replay.
Okay.
Well, dude, my brother, we
have, we've covered a lot.
The only thing we didn't cover today is
we have a, um, we have a business, uh,
thing that I promised I'd,
I'd, uh, talk about here.
A business thing?
Yeah.
A business thing.
Yes.
So, so people know that our,
our new project is called Godcaster
and it's a really interesting problem.
So at the beginning we needed a placeholder
for a logo and you did something in,
um, in, I don't know, some AI thing.
What'd you use for that?
Uh, mid journey.
Mid journey.
And it came up with this big G
and honestly, it's kind of grown,
it's kind of grown on me.
Um, I don't like the big G.
Yeah.
Um, but we do have a small budget available
for anyone who wants to create a logo.
And if we use it, then we'll
gladly buy it from you.
And, uh, and it's only for this group.
We're not going to talk
about it anywhere else.
So if anybody, I mean, and it can
be prompt jockeyed or whatever.
Uh, but we'd love to have
some options to choose
from because we're
building our website and
we're, and we're, you know, we're getting
all kinds of things ready to market it.
So it would be great.
If anyone is interested, ping me
and, uh, and we'll see if, you know,
and I'll let you know what we're doing.
But it has to be rad.
Oh no, it's gotta be rad.
Obviously you're doing it for Jesus.
Come on.
You can't, you can't do
something for Jesus.
It's not rad.
It's gotta be rad.
Get that out of here.
Uh, let's thank some people,
uh, before we leave.
Um, we have a Chad F who
boosted a thousand sats.
Uh, it says listening live while I'm
alive by Abel James live on PC 2.0.
Thank you.
That's lost on Linux.
Uh, also, um, uh, boosted,
uh, for, um, Abel James.
And he just says, bye-bye Spotify.
Uh, 19,000 sats from user 36219770
over there on the fountains.
Merry Christmas boardroom.
Yeah, that guy's great.
Uh, Sam Sethi, very active.
Uh, I'll do, uh, he has three.
No, he has many in her.
Here we go.
A thousand sats.
He says, Dave Weiner stole Netscape
0.91 from my friends who invented RSS.
Mike Holm and Dan Libby.
He then added a few updates
and call it RSS 2.0.
What a hypocrite.
Hey man, how come we didn't
say that on your show?
It doesn't count if
you're just boosting it.
It's in the Brian cut.
Thousand from Sam.
The install bar appears only if you
have IO and iOS app in the app store.
Apple want you to switch to
their proprietary app store.
Welcome to my world.
Frowny face.
Yeah, but if anybody understands
the, the depths of, of, of, of PWA.
You mean universal apps.
I'm not going to, I'm never
going to use the term PWA again.
It's going to be universal app.
Um, by the way, what?
So when P when people hit the little
mobile icon on, on the Godcaster,
that should pop up some,
something that says,
here's how you install it based upon
the OS or the browser or whatever.
It just, it just hit me.
I'm going to file it.
I'm a horrible GitHub filer.
Uh, triple seven from, you don't do it.
That's right.
Triple seven from Sam Sethi universal
app install once run everywhere.
Yeah.
Dude, that's something like that.
See loss on Linux 1111 rename
podcasting 2.0 to podcasting plus plus.
No, we're not renaming anything.
It has no name.
We're just a bunch of people
making podcasting better.
Sam, man, stop drinking
wine while boosting.
It's illegal in the UK.
He says a thousand.
No, don't stop.
There's only one pussy.
I want to call out Rip Van Weiner.
Okay.
Well, she's.
Hey, it's your, it's your sats, man.
You can do whatever you want.
Uh, pod two.
Uh, I think that's Russell 33,
33 decentralization thrives
on diversity and innovation.
No idea better than another
until it's proven supporting
new ideas of multiple systems ensures
as we grow stronger together.
Instead of dismissing,
let's build, collaborate,
and foster a culture where
creativity leads the way.
Hashtag decentralization.
Hashtag innovation.
Hashtag build together.
Well, I think we covered all that.
Yep.
For sure.
Alberto at rss.com.
Coming in from podcast
guru with a thousand sats.
Got a bunch of, uh, uh, rocket
ships and a Christmas tree.
Thank you.
Nice rocket Christmas tree.
Yes.
And, uh, I've hit the delimiter.
So you're up.
Oh, that's me.
Okay.
Uh, let's see.
We have, we had no, uh, one, one off PayPal's,
but we have, uh, some booster grams.
Let me see.
Uh, here I had to resort my emails.
I'm now up to 1178 unread emails.
It's my inbox.
Let's see.
Uh, but I did, I did
actually do some admin work.
I mean, this morning on your,
on your, oh yeah, I saw it.
Yeah.
You were helping people.
The help desk came through.
Yeah.
I'm like, wow, look at that.
Look at that.
You're like, oh, I didn't
have to do that one.
Okay.
Uh, let's see.
Uh, I see lots on Linux.
Uh, one, I see a satchel of
Richard through fountain.
He says, I concur about 20,000 Hertz
being a really interesting podcast.
Hmm.
Uh, that must be a comment.
I don't remember that one.
Uh, Cole McCormick, satchel
of Richard through fountain.
He says, uh, boosting in from Disneyland,
the forces with the podcasting 2.0 crew.
Wow.
Oh, from Disneyland.
He's committed.
Oh, Kyron mere mortals.
Satchel Richards through fountain.
He says, just some words
of encouragement to all.
I regularly scour around
the crypto space to see
if there are any other projects addressing
the value needs of musicians,
podcasters, and artists in general.
Everything I see is centralized
and dependent on one chain.
This is the only project that
has the solid foundation
for distributed RSS and adaptable
protocol, the namespace and value tag,
and the ethos to make it all make sense.
V4V international lifestyle.
Despite the Albie blip, I
am more enthused than ever.
I love you all.
And we love you too, Kyron.
I, uh, I invited my, uh, my friend Mark
Hall to Antone's and, um, uh, he's,
he's the documentarian.
He has a documentary of the Killing Ed
documentary put up a long time ago on video.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
On, uh, in A2.
Yes.
And, uh, he says, oh, this is value
for value and boosting and all that.
It says, will my Hawk to a coin work?
I'm like, okay, the deaf, the,
the shining example of rug pull.
Yeah.
Right.
Poor girl.
She got screwed over, man.
She got an agent and then a bunch of
shysters moved in, uh, Cole McCormick,
uh, Satchel Richards through fountain.
He says, I would like to
encourage more thought
and discussion around
more podcasting apps,
integrating Noster from my singular
perspective and experience.
I have really enjoyed
going back and forth on
fountain and primal also considering that
many V for V musicians are using it.
Open mic is into it for live events.
I think it makes sense for the
apps to go where the artists are.
That's, that's up to the apps.
It's up to the apps, right?
Yeah, that's exactly right.
That's what, that's the
part you can't control.
Uh, still lost on Linux.
Uh, another Satchel Richards, he said, he
says, I have super secret projects too.
They are so secret that I
don't even make them that way.
No one can ever know about it.
I know, right?
Those two.
Yeah.
Many of those, uh, delimiter,
capture blogger, 15,299 sats.
Nice.
Your fountain.
He says, hello, music
connoisseurs, Adam and Dave.
I have two things to share this time.
Firstly, please check out my song.
The lyrics were written
by me while the singing
and music were generated
through AI based on
my detailed prompts.
You can find it by visiting podcast
index.org and searching for CSB serenade.
Secondly, well, okay.
Let me, um, yeah, go
ahead and keep reading.
I'll look for it.
Secondly, Adam, could
you explain why some V4V
music podcasters refuse to
play music hosted on Wavelake?
I'm a bit confused about this.
Yo, CSB.
You'd have to ask them, DSB.
I don't really know.
That's a, I mean, I have
my thoughts about it.
Let's listen to, this is the, uh,
eclair serenade by comic strip
blogger who was actually,
Oh man, I got to put
this in the value split.
Hold on.
I got those urges inside, but the
call of sweetness I could not hide.
It's always easy to resist the dream.
Okay.
This has, if, if anybody knows
the, uh, the theme song,
the GLaDOS theme song from Portal,
that's, it gives me those vibes for sure.
I don't know anything about it.
Yeah.
That's definitely some Portal vibes.
Uh, we got some, uh, some monthlies.
We got Lauren Ball, $24.20.
Uh, Podverse, Mitch and the boys, $50.
Thank you.
Beautiful.
Basil Phillip, $25.
Christopher Harbaric, $10.
Mitch Downey, $10.
Hadn't heard from, uh,
Sir Mitch in a while.
Yeah.
Terry Keller, $5.
Chris Cowan, $5.
Silicone Florist, $10.
Yara and Rosenstein, $1.
Damon Kasajak, $15.
Paul Saltzman, $22.22.
And Derek J. Visker, $21.
Thank you all very much.
And a late boost from, uh, Sir Libre.
Lightning thrashes, a short
row of ducks, $22.22.
Great meeting as always.
I'm glad things seem to be settling down.
We've got the best devs in the universe.
There's nothing they can't accomplish.
I agree.
Nice.
Dude, we have like a whole 10 minutes
left if you want to talk about something.
Or do you just want to get
back to your exciting day job?
The problem is we don't have time to get
into the other thing that I want to talk.
Yeah.
That I want to talk about.
All right.
Um, well, um, let's talk about this.
Go ahead.
No, no, please go.
No, I was just going to
say, do you see, uh,
Kara and Prof G are going
to sell their podcast
for, uh, eight figures.
They're going to sell their podcast?
No.
Where was this?
No, it was in hot, uh,
hot pod is a hot pod.
The Bloomberg, the
Bloomberg newsletter thing.
It's for sale.
Uh, it was on, uh, let's see.
Let's see what, uh, Ashley says.
Yeah.
Pivot goes to market.
Scott Galloway and Kara
Swisher have become two
of the biggest stars in
podcasting, blah, blah, blah.
Uh, this coming year, the,
their deal with Vox will be up
and they've already begun seeking
a potentially new partner for their flagship
program, as well as the other shows,
as well as their other shows while
asking for an up to eight figure sum,
according to people familiar
with the conversations.
Well, that's interesting
because James on pod news,
weekly review had a piece from the
Prof G podcast saying that that podcast
brings in $8 million a year pivot.
He said 10.
I thought it was eight to 10.
Okay.
Maybe 10, okay.
$10 million a year.
Why would you want, why would you
want to sell that to somebody?
This take the cashflow, you dummies.
This is the, it's bullshit is what it is.
Yeah.
This is, this is using
his podcast to, to Jack,
to say publicly that
they're making a lot of
money to try to jack up the offers.
That's what it sounds like to me.
I mean, that's a, that's a lot of
money and why would Vox give that up?
This is, well, the, the,
the other part of the story said
that Vox still owns the feed.
So any deal would have
to include the feed.
Otherwise they would have to,
and this is the other thing
that doesn't make any sense.
So she says in this, what's
the name of this newsletter?
Soundbite.
Let me see if, yes.
With a Y?
I thought you got this newsletter.
I don't think so.
Soundbite.
And who, who writes it?
It's Bloomberg.
It's Ashley Carmen.
Oh, Bloomberg.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
Soundbite.
Bloomberg.
Got it.
But she says pivot remains
their most popular offering
with over 278,000 followers on Spotify.
So you have 278,000 subscribers
and you make $10 million a year.
How's those numbers don't add up to me?
Sounds a little sketchy.
Mm-hmm.
I mean, I know that's only on
Spotify, but I mean, that's,
that would be a global number.
So let me, let's say, let's say
double, let's say it's double that.
Let's say you have another
278,000 on, on Apple.
And they have, okay.
So they, let's do the numbers.
So they have, so let's say that,
well, let's say they have a million.
Why just do a million?
Let's do a million.
All right.
So that's a thousand CPMs.
They have six spots, right?
So times six.
Do they have six spots?
Yeah.
Times six times, let's, let's
say they're really great.
30.
Okay.
So what is that?
A second.
Calculator.
Come on, chat GPT.
So it's one, one, two, three
thousand times six times 30 is, wow.
So they have $180,000 an
episode and then times
they do twice weekly times 110 is, wow.
$19 million.
Something's wrong.
Something's off with these numbers.
I'm sure that not every
spot gets a $30 CPM.
Maybe only the first one.
Well, yeah.
Oh yeah, for sure.
I mean, if you have like a post
roll or something like that,
that's not going to get a $30 CPM.
It's not going to get a $30 CPM.
And plus, I mean, you're, you
said a million followers.
I don't think they get there.
Well, I'm just thinking, I'm just
thinking, I'm just thinking,
I'm just thinking, screw
this value for value stuff.
Dvorak and I should go for, for CPMs, man.
We'll, we'll make a
killing four more years.
Exit strategy.
You'll make a killing and you'll
kill the show in six months.
Within six hours.
Yeah.
78,000 followers on Spotify.
I'm thinking 600,000 total, maybe
followers across all platforms.
And that translates into,
let's say 600,000 downloads.
Well, what they have is they
have very high end advertisers.
And this, this is what bothers me.
They're a so-called tech show.
But you know, when Apple
advertises on your show,
are you really going to tell people that
Apple intelligence sucks?
Or are you going to
say, it's great, Scott?
Well, how many, how many shows
do they do per week of pivot?
Two.
Okay.
So that's, that's, uh,
that's 1,200 CPM, right?
Cause you got, you got 600,000,
which it would be 600 CPM times two,
1,200 times 20, let's
just say, uh, $30 CPM.
Yeah.
$36,000 an episode.
Ah, my math was off by amazing amounts.
Yes.
Uh, no, that's, that's $36,000 a week.
I'm sorry.
So we times 52, right?
That's, uh, 1.9 million,
that's $2 million a year.
Yeah.
That sounds reasonable.
That sounds more like what it
probably is, but you know,
taking high end advertisers, they
could be asking a huge
amount and they read them.
So you don't know, you don't know
what the deal is, but I think 10,
10 million and then saying we're for sale.
Uh, okay.
To speak with prof G language.
If I were you boss, uh,
I would get my own sales team and
just get the Rolodex that you
already have and take the money.
Why, why do you need it up front?
You're all rich.
Yeah.
I mean, and yeah, and they
both already have money.
So, I mean, like this is just, uh, yeah, I
don't, that didn't make any sense to me.
Smells like a scam.
Yeah.
I mean, if you're, if you have,
I mean, I'm sure they're making,
I'm sure they're, I'm
sure they're making seven figures easily.
I mean, they're making probably,
you know, 5 million or something.
It wouldn't, wouldn't surprise
me because, you know,
advertise as advertising goes up
and down, but nobody, I don't,
I just don't see how anybody's
going to come in and buy
them for what, like 20 million
or something like that.
Why would they do that?
Hmm.
Well, I will be interested to hear that.
I think they have a new
show coming out today.
So maybe they talk about it.
It's my hate.
Listen, can't wait.
I'm excited.
Hate listens are the best.
I've dropped the ball on, on the media.
Oh yeah.
It's been, it's been a little hard.
Yeah.
Ever since they've,
they self-analyzed that
no one cares about them when they thought
that everyone, they were important.
That's when it was still cool.
That was still a good hate.
Listen, all right, I'm
letting you off, brother.
You got five minutes.
This is perfect.
Actually, we're at top of the hour.
Got to go home.
And thank you very much boardroom.
Thank you for being here.
We will not have a show
next week because I will
be in transit from Amsterdam to Italy.
And we probably won't have
a show the week after
that because it's the day after Christmas.
It's the day after Christmas.
Is Christmas on a Wednesday this year?
It'll be two days after Christmas.
Yeah.
Well, I'm sorry.
In Europe, they celebrate
two days of Christmas.
They have Christmas on the 25th.
You get double Christmas in Europe?
You do.
Well, in the UK, it's called Boxing Day.
Okay.
And in the rest of Europe, it's
called Second Christmas Day.
I swear to God.
No, you're kidding.
Yes.
It's literally called Second Christmas?
Second Christmas Day.
Yes.
I feel cheated now.
I want two Christmases, too.
And we will be flying back on that Friday.
So it looks like we'll
be off for two weeks.
But then we'll be cracking
in the new year with
brand new Podcasting 2.0 board meetings.
Brother Dave, have a great weekend.
How are you, too, man?
Everybody, thank you so
much for being here.
We love you.
We appreciate you.
We'll see you in the new
year right here on 2.0.
You have been listening to Podcasting 2.0.
Visit podcastindex.org
for more information.
Go podcasting!
I don't want your left-wing app.
I don't want your lefty app.